<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Real-Time Rendering on RenderForge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/real-time-rendering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Real-Time Rendering on RenderForge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 05:21:43 +0330</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/real-time-rendering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gandom Rasterizer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gandom-rasterizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 05:21:43 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gandom-rasterizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gandom is a software rasterizer that mimics algorithms which are behind graphics APIs and even what are implemented physically on GPU dies.
In this project, I have implemented the processes used by graphics APIs
and GPUs to render and synthesize an image for display,
implemented entirely in code running on a CPU. For the performance issues
I leveraged SIMD instructions (AVX2) to improve its performance.
I implemented key algorithms of the graphics pipeline,
such as triangle clipping, back-face culling, and scanline rasterization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noora Ray Tracer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/noora-ray-tracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 15:40:08 +0330</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/noora-ray-tracer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Noora is a ray tracer began as a deep dive into the algorithms that bring virtual scenes to life. Starting with Peter Shirley&amp;rsquo;s accessible guides, I built a functional Monte Carlo path tracer—an offline renderer that simulates complex lighting effects like caustics and diffuse inter-reflection by tracing the path of light through a scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, it is an offline renderer capable of producing images with global illumination, soft shadows, and realistic materials, but I am developing a GPU-accelerated, real-time version to explore the performance and algorithmic trade-offs between offline and interactive rendering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
